A Guide to the Papers of Edward E. Younger, 1937-1979
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
- VIII. Student Subject Files
  - Morrison, James Lunford, Jr. 1960-1970 (Box 74)
  - Moss, Bobby 1965-1971 (Box 74)
  - Mugleston, William F. 1967 (Box 74)
  - Murray, Walter M. 1965 (Box 74)
  - Noel, Edgar Estes 1960-1977 (Box 74)
  - Nolan, John M. 1964-1971 (Box 74)
  - Ours, Robert M. 1964-1969 (Box 74)
  - Pandya, Mithilesh 1958-1962 (Box 74)
  - Parker, William L. 1965 (Box 74)
  - Pendleton, Eldridge H. 1970 (Box 74)
  - Peterson, Rena Hayes 1965 (Box 74)
  - Peterson, Richard 1972-1973 (Box 74)
  - Poindexter, Harry E. 1960-1969 (Box 74)
  - Porter, Julian Patrick, Jr. 1966-1967 (Box 74)
  - Pulley, Ray & Judith 1963-1972 (Box 74)
  - Pyron, Darden n.d. (Box 74)
  - Rainbolt, Charles 1970-1972 (Box 74)
  - Poston, Charles E. 1963-1971 (Box 74)
  - Quinn, Jack T. 1963-1966 (Box 74)
  - Ray, William G. 1967-1972 (Box 74)
  - Rea, Robert Right 1964 (Box 74)
  - Readnour, Harry W. n.d. (Box 74)
  - Reed, Patrick 1972-1978 (Box 74)
  - Reid, Lota S. 1965 (Box 74)
  - Rhodes, William 1966-1977 (Box 75)
  - Ritch, William N. 1971-1975 (Box 75)
  - Robert, Mrs. Jean T. 1965 (Box 75)
  - Robertson, William Glenn 1966-1978 (Box 75)
  - Robilotti, Richard V. 1965-1967 (Box 75)
  - Rochester, Stuart I. 1966-1976 (Box 75)
  - Roebuck, James R. 1966-1969 (Box 75)
  - Rose, Joseph W. 1965 (Box 75)
  - Rose, Stanley 1966-1971 (Box 75)
  - Rosen, Phillip A. 1971-1973 (Box 75)
  - Rucker, Warren P. 1970 (Box 75)
  - Saunders, Robert 1966-1977 (Box 75)
  - Schaffer, Alan 1961-1966 (Box 75)
  - Schrank, Marvin 1964 (Box 75)
  - Scribner, Robert L. 1971-1974 (Box 75)
  - Sexton, Mary Dubois 1972-1977 (Box 75)
  - Sharma, Jagdish P. 1963 (Box 75)
  - Sharma, Miriam 1965-1970 (Box 75)
  - Shaughnessy, Margaret J. Pherson 1971 (Box 75)
  - Shelton, Charlotte Jean 1969-1979 (Box 75)
  - Shi, David 1973-1978 (Box 75)
  - Shibley, Ronald E. 1966-1973 (Box 75)
  - Shiflett, Crandall A. 1970 (Box 75)
  - Simmons, Dennis E. 1975-1978 (Box 75)
  - Simms, Moody 1962-1966 (Box 76)
  - Smith, Douglas 1959-1972 (Box 76)
  - Smith, Gloria Galban 1957-1961 (Box 76)
  - Smith, James Douglas 1964-1969 (Box 76)
  - Stauffenburg, Ann Lenore 1970-1973 (Box 76)
  - Suggs, Henry Lewis 1971-1979, 2 folders (Box 76)
  - Summers, Virginia M. 1965 (Box 76)
  - Tarter, Joe Brent 1972-1979 (Box 76)
  - Tanner, Douglas W. 1967-1973 (Box 76)
  - Taylor, Richard L. 1964-1972 (Box 76)
  - Taylor, Robert T. 1957 (Box 76)
  - Ten Broeck, James Robertson 1964-1966 (Box 76)
  - Thiemeyer, Jay 1971 (Box 76)
  - Thompson, Paul 1961-1969 (Box 76)
  - Toepfer, Marcia 1971-1973 (Box 76)
  - Toone, William G. 1965 (Box 76)
  - Tripathi, Chandra Bhushan 1959-1974 (Box 76)
  - Troy, Helen 1976 (Box 76)
  - Van Steeg, Clarence L. 1965-1966 (Box 76)
  - Vogt, George L. 1970-1978 (Box 76)
  - Wagenblast, Dennis F. 1973 (Box 76)
  - Wagle, Narendra Kashinath 1962-1964 (Box 76)
  - Waits, John A. 1971-1976 (Box 76)
  - Watts, James D./ 1965 (Box 76)
  - Webster, Michael Gordon 1964 (Box 76)
  - Wehrle, Edmund S. 1966 (Box 77)
  - Weisiger, Minor 1975-1979 (Box 77)
  - West, Frank 1965-1968 (Box 77)
  - Wheaton, Kathleen 1973 (Box 77)
  - Wiley, Wayne H. 1971-1973 (Box 77)
  - Williams, Bette Harris 1971 (Box 77)
  - Willis, Leo Stanley 1962-1968 (Box 77)
  - Willis, Sara 1968 (Box 77)
  - Winters, Marvin E. 1967-1970 (Box 77)
  - Woodruff, Albert H. 1967-1968 (Box 77)
  - Wolfe, Jonathan J. 1966-1970 (Box 77)
  - Wood, Nicholas Worthington 1971-1973 (Box 77)
  - Wynes, Charles 1958-1978 (Box 77)
  - Young, Lowell T. 1969-1979 (Box 77)
  - Zuckerman, Bernice Bryant 1963-1969 (Box 77)
  - Letters of Recommendation 1948-1953, 1961-1964, 1966-1973, 1974-1976, n.d., 4 folders (Box 77)
- Oversize Items
  - Reproduction of newspaper The Western Spy1800 Feb. 12
  - Electrostatic copies, primarily newspaper clippings from the Iowa State Register collected for Kasson biography 1862-1866, Galleys
  - Albemarle: Jefferson's County ca. 1975, Galleys
  - Certificate of Recognition of Edward Younger, awarded by Governor John N. Dalton 1978
  - Cartoon re History Department n.d.
- Tape Recordings
  - "Nineteenth Century Attitudes" first lecture in a series on "The United States in World Affairs" given by Edward Younger in India (text and related correspondence in collection) 1958 Jan 23, 3 7-inch reels
    T 766 a, b, c
  - Lecture by Younger re: The role of the historian in the contemporary world, with question/answer period; recorded at Bombay House I.C.W.A. ca. 1958, 3 7-inch reels
    T 765, a, b, c
  - Younger-tape from India, greetings and songs ca. 1958, 1 5-inch reel
    T 763
  - Music of India ca. 1958, 1 7-inch reel
    T 767
  - Dance music from India ca. 1958, 1 7-inch reel
    T 768
  - "Background of U.S. Global Strategic Commitments," a lecture by Younger at the 11th Global Strategy Session, Naval War College (text in collection) 1961 Jun 12, 1 7-inch reel
    T 758
  - Broadcast to India by Younger via Voice of America 1962 April, 1 7-inch reel
    T 760
  - "Colonialism, Nationalism, and Neutralism" - a lecture by Younger 1962 Nov 16, 1 7-inch reel (3.75 ips)
    T 761
  - "Neutralism" lecture by Younger at War College Air University, w/question/answer period (related correspondence in collection) ca. 1963, 1 7-inch reel
    T 764
  - Interview with Carter Lowance and Hobie Clairborne n.d., 1 cassette
    T 762
  - Albemarle County Historical Society Meetings
  - "Albemarle, National Leader in the Bicentennial Celebration" by Michael Gleason 1975 Feb 23, 1 7-inch reel
  - "The Bicentennial-A Preliminary Evaluation" by Norman Graebner 1975 May 28
  - "Carr's Hill of the University of Virginia" by Bruce L. Mertens 1975 Nov 2
  - "Richmond of Yesterday and Today" by Virginius Dabney 1975 Dec 7
  - "Mr. Jefferson's Grandchildren" by George Green Shackelford 1976 Mar 21
- 16 mm Motion Picture Film
  - "The Legacy of Thomas Jefferson" produced by Reader's Digest Films (time 3:10) n.d., 1 5-inch reel (B & W, no sound)